<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" 
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
    xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
	<channel>
<title>Abbie Codes</title><link>https://abbiecod.es/index.html</link><description>News from Abbie</description><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:creator>Abbie Gonzalez</dc:creator><dc:date>2011-05-23T16:09:17-04:00</dc:date><admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="http://www.realmacsoftware.com/" />
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<sy:updateBase>2000-01-01T12:00+00:00</sy:updateBase>
<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 22:58:49 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>New App: Overlays&#x21;</title><dc:creator>Abbie Gonzalez</dc:creator><dc:subject>News</dc:subject><dc:date>2015-08-22T22:59:39-04:00</dc:date><link>https://abbiecod.es/news/files/new-app-overlays.html#unique-entry-id-0</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://abbiecod.es/news/files/new-app-overlays.html#unique-entry-id-0</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="readingLineIconMult-512" src="https:/abbiecod.es/news/files/readinglineiconmult-512.png" width="128" height="128" /></div>It started as an app I wrote for myself. I shared an older Windows version some time back, but I&rsquo;ve updated it, and added a MacOS version now to. Read more on it&rsquo;s app page.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The New Testament&#x2c; In OpenDyslexic</title><dc:creator>Abbie Gonzalez</dc:creator><dc:subject>News</dc:subject><dc:date>2013-01-03T19:56:43-05:00</dc:date><link>https://abbiecod.es/news/files/the-new-testament-in-OpenDyslexic.html#unique-entry-id-2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://abbiecod.es/news/files/the-new-testament-in-OpenDyslexic.html#unique-entry-id-2</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img class="imageStyle" alt="P1020004" src="https:/abbiecod.es/news/files/p1020004.jpg" width="150" height="150" />It was originally going to just be just a gift for my wife, but so many wanted one, I worked on making a version I was comfortable selling: a thinner, better, more professional looking New Testament with a table of contents.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ERBrowser adds support for OpenDyslexic</title><dc:creator>Abbie Gonzalez</dc:creator><dc:subject>News</dc:subject><dc:date>2012-10-20T23:02:30-04:00</dc:date><link>https://abbiecod.es/news/files/er-browser-adds-support-for-opendyslexic.html#unique-entry-id-1</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://abbiecod.es/news/files/er-browser-adds-support-for-opendyslexic.html#unique-entry-id-1</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="App-Version-1.3-Promo" src="https:/abbiecod.es/news/files/app-version-1.3-promo.jpg" width="640" height="350" /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Increasing Support for OpenDyslexic</title><dc:creator>Abbie Gonzalez</dc:creator><dc:subject>News</dc:subject><dc:date>2012-10-15T20:58:55-04:00</dc:date><link>https://abbiecod.es/news/files/increasing-support-for-opendyslexic.html#unique-entry-id-3</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://abbiecod.es/news/files/increasing-support-for-opendyslexic.html#unique-entry-id-3</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[Wow! It's been an amazing few weeks! Right after Instapaper added support for OpenDyslexic, emails and comments poured in. Interview requests filled my inbox. Downloads went through the roof. And thousands of people found a free way to help with their dyslexia symptoms. <br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>OpenDyslexic mentions and uses</title><dc:creator>Abbie Gonzalez</dc:creator><dc:subject>News</dc:subject><dc:date>2012-09-13T15:40:20-04:00</dc:date><link>https://abbiecod.es/news/files/open-dyslexic-mentions-and-uses.html#unique-entry-id-4</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://abbiecod.es/news/files/open-dyslexic-mentions-and-uses.html#unique-entry-id-4</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[OpenDyslexic has been around for less than a year, downloaded over 12,500 times, and it has already found many uses:<br /><br />WordSmith: An ex<a href="http://helpforstrugglingreaders.blogspot.com/2012/02/helpful-apps-for-dyslexia-and-related.html"></a>cellent new word processor for the professional writer using MacOS, WordSmith has an optional theme, &ldquo;Irving,&rdquo; that uses OpenDyslexic as the typeface (and which I'm using to write this). <a href="http://plowsoftware.com/wordsmith/styles/">http://plowsoftware.com/wordsmith/styles/</a><br /><br />iPhoneRuler has BytaFont theme for jailbroken iPhones to change the default iOS font to OpenDyslexic. In it&rsquo;s first 6 weeks of release, it has seen 6,419 installs, and has become the #31 most appreciated typeface. <a href="http://www.iphoneruler.net/2012/08/open-dyslexic-font.html">http://www.iphoneruler.net/2012/08/open-dyslexic-font.html</a><br /><br />The open source iPad ebook reader, Dox on Box, uses OpenDyslexic with it&rsquo;s innovative colorization techniques to make reading ebooks on the iPad easier. <a href="https://github.com/snarshad/doxonbox">https://github.com/snarshad/doxonbox</a><br /><br />The Magic Judge Wiki recommends using OpenDyslexic for Judge exams. <a href="http://wiki.internationalmagicjudges.net/index.php/Certifying_Candidates_with_Dyslexia_or_Other_Learning_Disabilities">http://wiki.internationalmagicjudges.net/...</a><br /><br />Both openWeb and OpenDyslexic receive a mention here: <a href="http://helpforstrugglingreaders.blogspot.com/2012/02/helpful-apps-for-dyslexia-and-related.html">http://helpforstrugglingreaders.blogspot.com/2012/02/helpful-apps-for-dyslexia-and-related.html</a><br /><br />OpenDyslexic, thanks to your help, is now almost fully complete. Font smoothing on Windows is still being worked out, but on platforms written by sane people (Every platform but Windows), that is not an issue. <br /><br />Edit: As you can tell, if you are reading this right now, this list became just a small list in the span of a week! I really need to write an update post. As soon as I'm not overwhelmed with work, I will. Thank you all. 2012/09/13]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Remove the Title Bar from Gnome 3 on Maximize</title><dc:creator>Abbie Gonzalez</dc:creator><dc:subject>News</dc:subject><dc:date>2011-05-29T16:04:57-04:00</dc:date><link>https://abbiecod.es/news/files/removing-the-title-bar-from-gnome3-on-maximize.html#unique-entry-id-5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://abbiecod.es/news/files/removing-the-title-bar-from-gnome3-on-maximize.html#unique-entry-id-5</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[Gnome 3 has a wonderful UI, but one glaring fault. The top system bar serves as a "title bar" for your current application, telling you what app you have open, and allowing you to exit the application from the bar itself. Unfortunately, the default theme, Adwaita, has huge looking titlebars, which don't really get in the way when you are working in normal sized windows. When the windows are maximized though, you have 2 titlebars taking up precious screen realestate: the big Adwaita titlebar, and the system bar up top. <br /><br />Fortunately its real easy to fix this.<br /><br />Open your Adwaita xml (/usr/share/themes/Adwaita/metacity-1/metacity-theme-3.xml) file and change the line that configures the maximized window (name="max"). Add has_title="false" to the "frame_geometry" tag. Then look for "title_vertical_pad", and change "value=9" to value="1". Restart Gnome 3 and maximize a window. *poof* the UI makes sense now.<br /><br />Interestingly, you can still drag down from a menu or button bar to return to a normal sized window and get your duplicate titlebar back. ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Announcing Distress Signal: Community Run Emergency Notifications</title><dc:creator>Abbie Gonzalez</dc:creator><dc:subject>News</dc:subject><dc:date>2011-05-23T16:09:17-04:00</dc:date><link>https://abbiecod.es/news/files/announcing-distress-signal-community-run-emergency-notifications.html#unique-entry-id-8</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://abbiecod.es/news/files/announcing-distress-signal-community-run-emergency-notifications.html#unique-entry-id-8</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<iframe frameborder="0" height="410px" src="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/abbie/distress-signal-community-centered-emergency-notif/widget/video.html" width="480px"></iframe><br /><p>I&rsquo;ve been slightly silently working on a <a href="http://kck.st/mhemvi">project that I&rsquo;ve now placed on Kickstarter</a>. It&rsquo;s a decentralized emergency dispatch network that can be run by communities and groups apart from 911. The decentralized approach prevents disasters from completely disabling it, or governments from blocking access. This also allows for municipalities to be less tied up in emergencies that do not require 911. </p><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Customizing the Command Menu Fader in Ares</title><dc:creator>Abbie Gonzalez</dc:creator><dc:subject>News</dc:subject><dc:date>2011-01-24T16:08:00-05:00</dc:date><link>https://abbiecod.es/news/files/customizing-the-command-menu-fader-in-ares.html#unique-entry-id-7</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://abbiecod.es/news/files/customizing-the-command-menu-fader-in-ares.html#unique-entry-id-7</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[I just spent the better part of the morning searching Google, trying to figure out how to get a black fader in the Command Menu using Ares. I searched everywhere in Palm's documentation and their forums. The best solution I could find was the instruction on <a title="MenuFade Non-solution" href="http://developer.palm.com/distribution/viewtopic.php?f=11&amp;t=5181&amp;p=23266&amp;hilit=command+menu+fade#p23266">this forum post</a>:<br /><blockquote>Add menuClass: 'no-fade' to your command menu attributes and that will remove the fade.</blockquote><br />And that was to the same question I had. Talk about a non-solution! That was all I had: How do you change the command menu fade? You don't! After a few hours of searching, that was all I had, and it bothered me. Then I remembered that with Ares, webOS apps are running in a browser... *almost* any browser you choose. I fired up Safari, and after a few element inspections, I had the code necessary to change the command menu fader.<br /><blockquote>.palm-menu.command-menu.palm-dark &gt; .palm-menu-fade {<br />background: url(../path/to/file.png) bottom left repeat-x;<br />}</blockquote><br />And then, instead of changing menuClass to 'no-fade', I changed it to 'palm-dark' (menuClass: "palm-dark"). Of course, the class name does not have to be palm-dark, I just named it that because it fit.<br /><br />All the mucking about the internet was not in vain. I also found an O'Reilly Quick Reference guide that listed the two official menuClass properties that work with Mojo out of the box: palm-default and palm-white. palm-default is the normal cream-colored fade, and palm-white is a white version (that, honestly, the Palm Facebook app should use instead of the cream one). I have example images of each below.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Make Windows Fonts Readable with gdi++</title><dc:creator>Abbie Gonzalez</dc:creator><dc:subject>News</dc:subject><dc:date>2009-04-23T16:07:20-04:00</dc:date><link>https://abbiecod.es/news/files/make-windows-fonts-readable-with-gdi.html#unique-entry-id-6</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://abbiecod.es/news/files/make-windows-fonts-readable-with-gdi.html#unique-entry-id-6</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[An excellent <a href="http://www.grc.com/ct/ctwhat.htm">research paper by Steve Gibson</a> explains better than I can some very good reasons to despise Cleartype, and Microsoft font rendering techniques. This, I believe, is reason enough to make every computer you own a Macintosh, or at least attempt to install MacOS on your computers. Unless you enjoy reading at the MS mandated font size using the MS mandated fonts under cleartype (which is good, but I don't prefer the MS recommended settings).<br /><br />Well, I am cheap, and even though Apple hardware is typically cheaper than comparable non-Apple hardware, I am not in the market for that kind of hardware. As such, I have used Windows, and the Safari browser for reading on Windows (Safari uses the MacOS font technology). That is, until about a month ago, when I read <a href="http://vladg.com/2009/03/make-windows-fonts-look-as-smooth-as-mac-os-x-fonts/">this post about gdi++</a>. I use gdi++ under Windows now, and am not forced to use Safari at all anymore. Now I am back to using Opera on my $300 Acer laptop, and the text is much more readable. The Japanese developers of this software have my gratitude. :)]]></content:encoded></item></channel>
</rss>